Guide to the Eva Overton Lewis and Julian Herman Lewis, MD, PhD Collection circa 1887-2015
University of Chicago Library
- Series III: Lewis Family Papers
  - Subseries 10: Photographs and Audiovisual Materials
    - Photographs – Trip to East coast? Buildings and people including Ida Taylor Jones, Eva Overton Lewis, and Anthony Overton, circa 1910s (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Photographic negatives – Lewis family and friends, 1910s-1920s (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Photograph – People seated in chairs on lawn listening to man sing or orate. Military or college band in background. Circa 1910s-1920s (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Photographs – Group photos including Eva Overton Lewis, circa 1910s-1920s (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Photograph – Unidentified men, circa 1910s-1920s (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Photographs – Exteriors of houses with unidentified people nearby, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Photographs – Eva Overton [Lewis] on University of Chicago campus, circa 1912-1916 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Photographs – Eva Overton [Lewis], circa 1912-1918 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Photograph – Ida Taylor Jones, circa 1912-1916 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Photographs – Eva Overton [Lewis] and friends on University of Chicago campus, including Ida Taylor Jones, 1914 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Photographs – Group photographs including Julian H. Lewis in Washington Park, 1914 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Photograph – Lloyd A. Hall, 1914 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Photograph – Henry Binga Dismond, University of Chicago Track and Field, circa 1915-1916 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Photograph – “Bill,” 1916 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Photographs – Eva Overton [Lewis] in graduation cap and gown, circa 1916 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Photographs – Women in graduation caps and gowns, including Ida Taylor Jones, circa 1916 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Photograph – Group photo including Anthony Overton, Eva Overton Lewis, Ida Taylor Jones, and Clara Gregg Overton, circa 1916-1919 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Photographs – Eva Overton [Lewis] with friends, circa 1918 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Photograph – Eva Overton Lewis in wedding gown, September 1918 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Reproduction of photograph of Eva Overton Lewis in wedding gown, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Photograph – Eva Overton Lewis and bridesmaids, including Ida Taylor Jones, September 1918 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Photograph – George Ellis, studio portrait, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Photographs – Cordelia O. Lewis, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Photograph – Elise Evans, studio portrait, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis, circa 1920 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Photographs – Group photos including Eva Overton Lewis, Cordelia O. Lewis, Vesta Lewis, Frank [?], and Lizzie [?], circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Photograph – Ida Louise Young, age 8 months, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Photograph – Julian H. Lewis reading in laboratory, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Photograph on copper plate – Anthony Overton, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Photograph – John Calhoun Lewis studio portrait, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Photograph – Julian H. Lewis, studio portrait, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Photograph – Julian H. Lewis in laboratory, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Photographs – Julian H. Lewis in office and laboratory, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Photograph – Julian H. Lewis, studio portrait, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Photographs – Julian H. Lewis with groups of unidentified men [Alpha Phi Alpha at Tuskegee?], circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Photographs – Tuskegee University and Julian H. Lewis with groups of unidentified men [Alpha Phi Alpha?], circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Photographs – Unidentified people and Tuskegee University campus, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Photograph – University of Chicago campus, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Photographic negatives and print of photo of Lewis family changing car tire, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Photograph – Unidentified people, circa 1920s (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Photographs – Lewis children, 1920-1923 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis, circa 1921 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Photograph – Studio portrait of Julian H. Lewis, Eva Overton Lewis, Gloria Lewis, and Julian Lewis, Jr., circa 1912 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis and Julian Lewis, Jr.?, circa 1922 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Photograph – Julian Lewis, Jr., circa 1922 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Photograph – Julian H. Lewis and Gloria Lewis, circa 1922 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Photographic negatives – Lewis family, circa 1922-1925 and 1970s (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Photographs – Julian H. Lewis driving car and children standing on dirt road, circa 1923 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Photograph – Julian H. Lewis, Gloria Lewis, and Julian Lewis, Jr., circa 1924 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Photographs – Gloria Lewis and Julian Lewis, Jr., circa 1924-1925 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Photographs – Eva Overton Lewis, Gloria Lewis, Julian Lewis, Jr., circa 1925 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis, circa 1925 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Photograph – Lewis family at building site[?], circa 1925 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Photographs – Lewis family including Richard Hill, Eva Overton Lewis, Gloria Lewis, and Julian Lewis, Jr., 1926 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Photographs – V. Henry, Paris studio portraits of Gloria Lewis and Julian Lewis, Jr., circa 1926-1927 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Photographs – V. Henry, Paris studio portraits of Julian H. Lewis, Gloria Lewis, and Julian Lewis, Jr., circa 1926-1927 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Photograph – Eva Overton Lewis, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Photograph – Julian H. Lewis, Jr., circa 1927 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Photographs – Lewis children photographed outdoors near creek or river, circa 1928. Photos by Julian H. Lewis (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Photograph – Unidentified infants [John O. Lewis or Julian H. Lewis?] circa 1928 or 1892 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Photograph – John O. Lewis, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Photograph – Unidentified toddler [John O. Lewis?] in front of Christmas tree, circa 1929 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Photograph – Studio portrait of Julian H. Lewis, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Photograph – Julian Lewis, Jr., circa 1929-1931 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Photograph – Cordelia O. Lewis, John Calhoun Lewis, Gloria Lewis, John O. Lewis, Julian H. Lewis, Jr. seated on front steps, circa 1930 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Photographs – Julian H. Lewis in laboratory, circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Photograph – Julian H. Lewis standing in front of car, circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Photographs – Lewis children, circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Photograph – Louise [Lewis?] and Marguerite [?], circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis, circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Photographs – Wedding, circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Photograph – Lewis family [?] on dock overlooking lake, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis, circa 1930-1932 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis and John O. Lewis, circa 1930-1932 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Photograph – Julian H. Lewis holding fish, circa 1930-1942 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Photograph – Lewis family including Cordelia O. Lewis, John Calhoun Lewis, and children, circa 1932 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Photograph – John O. Lewis [?] and unidentified boy, circa 1932-1933 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Photographs – Studio portraits of Gloria Lewis, circa 1933-1935 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Photographs – Studio portraits of Gloria Lewis, circa 1936-1938 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Photograph – John O. Lewis [?], circa 1936-1938 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis, circa 1938 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Photographs – Kathryn [?] and unidentified teenage girl, circa 1938-1940 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis and unidentified woman on college campus, circa 1938-1942 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis, circa 1938-1945 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Photographs – Groups of young women (sorority?), one includes Gloria Lewis, circa 1938-1942 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis and group of young women in costumes, circa 1939-1940 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Photographs – Unidentified people, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Photograph – Julian H. Lewis, Jr., circa 1940 (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis and unidentified man, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Photograph – Exterior of home showing damage with police nearby, circa 1940s (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - Photograph – Julian Lewis and Eva Lewis, circa 1940-1945 (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - Photocopy of newspaper photo of John Calhoun Lewis, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Photograph – Gloria Lewis, “Uncle Everett,” and “Aunt Ida,” circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Photograph – “Muriel, Eunice, Alice,” circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - Photographic negatives, circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Photographic negatives, circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - Photographs – Formal portrait of Julian Lewis, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - Photographs – Julian H. Lewis seated at microscope. Unidentified woman seated across from him. Circa 1960s-1970s (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - Photograph – Lewis family seated at dining table, circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - Photographic negatives, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - Photograph – Cliffside carving in progress, undated (Box 10, Folder 63)
    - DVD – “The Life and Legacy of Julian H. Lewis, PhD/MD,” February 2015 (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - Photograph album pages, circa 1910s (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Group photograph of young women [Alpha Kappa Alpha?] dressed as younger girls with dolls and teddy bears – Eva Overton Lewis and Ida Taylor Jones pictured back row. Circa 1910s (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Studio portrait of Gloria Lewis, circa 1921 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Studio portrait of Julian H. Lewis, circa 1910s-1920s (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Studio portrait of Anthony Overton, circa 1920s (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Studio portrait of Anthony Overton, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Photograph of exterior of building – Switzerland [?], circa 1920s (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Studio portrait of unidentified woman, circa 1920s (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Wedding photograph – Julian Herman Lewis pictured left, circa 1920s (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Studio portrait of Julian H. Lewis, circa 1960s (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Studio portrait of Julian H. Lewis, circa 1960s (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Framed photograph of Alpha Kappa Alpha sorority, circa 1910s (Box 12)
  - Subseries 11: Artifacts and Textiles
    - Embroidery thread, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Beaded coin purse, leather matchbook case, and leather pouch, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Pearl collar necklace, undated (Box 14)
    - Ladies black high heel shoes, undated (Box 15)
    - Ladies tulle cap with green rosettes, circa 1920s (Box 16)
    - Tulle [veil?], undated (Box 17)
    - Carson Pirie Scott & Co box, undated (Box 18)
    - Black beaded dress, undated (Box 19)
    - Blue chiffon dress, undated (Box 20)
    - White beaded dress, undated (Box 21)
    - Blue beaded dress, undated (Box 22)
    - Wedding dress, 1918 (Box 23)
    - Purple and white felt pennant with oval photograph of Eva Overton Lewis and “EVA” stitched onto it, undated (Box 24)
  - Subseries 12: Oversize Documents
    - Vogue clipping featuring latest dress designs, circa 1920s (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Concert program – Leopold Godowsky, March 1927 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Julian H. Lewis' American Board of Pathology certificate, June 1944 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Eva Overton's University of Chicago diploma, 1915 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Map of view from Radcliffe Camera, Oxford, 1917 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Paris Maps – “Cook's Plan of Paris” and transportation map, circa 1926-1927 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Gloria Lewis, Chicago Public Schools certificate, Carter School, 1934 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Julian H. Lewis, Jr., Chicago Public Schools certificate, Carter School, 1934 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Gloria Lewis, Englewood High School diploma, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Eva Overton [Lewis] high school diploma and University of Chicago diploma, 1911 and 1916 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper – Chicago Bee, April 5, 1942 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper – Chicago Bee, May 24, 1942 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Clipping – Chicago Sun-Times, May 2, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper – The Daily Illini, December 8, 1911 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper – Daily Mail, September 4, 1926 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper – The Atlanta Independent, May 6, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper – The Cairo Evening Citizen, December 1, 1923 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper – The Cairo Evening Citizen, April 23, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper – The Cairo Evening Citizen, April 26, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper – The Chicago Bee, April 5, 1942 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper – The Chicago Daily News, November 11, 1918 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper – The Chicago Daily News, November 30, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper – The Chicago Daily News, December 11, 1936 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper – The Chicago Defender, November 20, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper – The Chicago Defender, July 15, 1933 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper – The Chicago Herald and Examiner – May 26, 1929 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper – The Chicago Tribune and the Daily News New York, June 20, 1927 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper – The Chicago Sunday Tribune, November 10, 1918 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper – The Chicago Sunday Tribune, June 28, 1931 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper – The Freeman, March 21, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper – The Michigan Chronicle, February 14, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper – The St. Louis Post-Dispatch, July 5, 1910 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper – The Standard News, June 30, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Maps, circa 1920s – First class plan of Cunard Line, S. S. “Aquitania” steamer; and map of Paris tourist attractions (OVERSIZE FOLDER 1)